Guide to the UNITE Records 1895-2011
UNITE Records
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
UNITE Records, 1895-2011
6000
Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE)
529 linear ft.
Audiovisual materials, memorabilia, pamphlets, papers, photographs, publications, records.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
SUBJECTS
Names:
Blackwell, Ron; Chishti, Muzaffar; Cowell, Susan; Eichler, Jeff; Gifford, Kathie Lee, 1953-; Howard, Alan; Mazur, Jay; Melman, David; Mort, Jo-Ann; Potofsky, Jacob; Proper, Carl; Quan, Katie; ABC Health Service Registry; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU); Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (ACWA); BMP America, Inc.; Crysteel Manufacturing, Inc.; Express Navigation; Fulton County Census of Business; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU); Lulu's Cafe; Monroe County (N.Y.) Visiting Nurses Association; Nationwide Precision Products Corporation; Party Rental Limited; Rochester (N.Y.) Visiting Nurses Association; SPX Corporation; Syracuse Gauge; Textile Workers Union of America (TWUA); Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE); UNITE HERE (Organization); Yale CO-OP; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Boston Joint Board
Subjects:
Clothing trade--New York (State); Clothing workers--Labor unions; Food service employees, Labor unions, New York (State); Health facilities, Employees, Labor unions, New York (State); Sweatshops, New York (State), New York; Textile industry--New York (State); Textile workers--Labor unions
Form and Genre Terms:
Audiovisual materials; Memorabilia; Pamphlets; Papers; Photographs; Publications
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Related Collections:
5983m: UNITE Convention Document
5619: ACWA/ACWTU Records
5780: ILGWU Records
6200: UNITE HERE Records
6299 MB: Kathy Andrade Collection of ILGWU and UNITE Quilts Memorabilia
6343 AV: Leonard Greenwald Collection of UNITE Audio-Visual Materials
6343 MB: Leonard Greenwald Collection of ACTWU and UNITE Memorabilia
6362: Alexandra Lescaze UNITE Cannon Fieldcrest Organizing Files
6362 AV: Alexandra Lescaze UNITE Cannon Fieldcrest Organizing Audio-Visual Materials
6362 P: Alexandra Lescaze UNITE Cannon Fieldcrest Organizing Photographs
CONTAINER LIST
- 6000 AV: UNITE Audio-Visual Collection, 1968-2003., Contains film, video, and audio recordings of music, including long time Vice President and Legislative Department Head Evelyn Dubrow, other union leaders, and covers issues such as diversity, worker strikes, working conditions, sweatshops including Kathy Lee Gifford interviews and pieces on Nike and Gap, Ann Hoffman on prison labor, NAFTA, and clothing imports.
- 6000 G: UNITE Posters, 1997-1998., Contains posters and broadsides in both English and Spanish.
- 6000 MB: UNITE Memorabilia., Contains mostly items for union members, such as pins, buttons, badges, tote bags, branded with the UNITE! logo.
- 6000 P: UNITE Photographs, 1926-2005., This collection has over 12,000 photographs, 400 slides and several CD's of photographs documenting the history of UNITE.
- 6000 PUBS: UNITE Publications., Contains the official union organ UNITE! in both English and Spanish. Also contains other periodicals, pamhlets, and other materials published for the union members.
- 6000/002: UNITE Founding Convention Poster, 1995-1998., Contains a poster from the founding convention and a Local 23-25 Rally poster.
- 6000/003: UNITE Research Department Historic Files, 1930-1999., Contains a compilation of ILGWU and ACTWU files from UNITE Research Department.
- 6000/007: UNITE Legislative Department Records, 1938-2006., Contains files on the White House Sweatshop Commission, child labor, comp time, health care, immigration, minimum wage, foreign/free trade, and other social or legal issues.
- 6000/007 AV: UNITE Legislative Department Audio-Visual Materials, 1989-2001., Contains VHS video tapes and audio cassettes on sweatshops, child labor, foreign/free trade, and other social or legal issues.
- 6000/008: UNITE Operations Department Collective Bargaining Agreements, 1895-1999., This collection includes files of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU) and the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) from both the Research Department and the Operations Department.
- 6000/010: UNITE President's Office Files, 1987-2003., Contains subject files, correspondence, General Executive Board meeting minutes, and other files from Jay Mazur's years as President of the union.
- 6000/012: UNITE Northeast Department Files, 1985-2000., Contains mostly employer negotiation and agreement files from UNITE, ILGWU, and ACTWU.
- 6000/012 AV: UNITE Northeast Department Audio-Visual Materials, 1985-1996., Contains mostly VHS video tapes. Many are recordings of TV news programs from the Scranton/Wilkes-Barre, PA, area. Also includes some tapes on sweatshops and foreign/free trade.
- 6000/012 P: UNITE Northeast Department Photographs, 1962-1994., This is a collection of over 1,500 photographs documenting UNITE's Northeast Dept.
- 6000/014: UNITE Research Department Chronological Correspondence Files, 1995-1997., Contains correspondence from the Research Department of UNITE, with the earliest ones being from Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU).
- 6000/016: UNITE Local 169 Files, 1990-2003., Contains employer files from predominantly New York State businesses.
- 6000/016 MB: UNITE Local 169 Amalgamated Northeast Regional Joint Board Memorabilia Banners., Includes banners from ILGWU and ACTWU, as well as UNITE banners.
- 6000/016 P: UNITE Local 169 Amalgamated Northeast Regional Joint Board Photographs, 1944-2003., This collection includes photographs from the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU), Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (ACWA), Textile Workers Union of America (TWUA), and Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).
- 6000/018: UNITE Pacific Northwest District Council Files, 1992-1998., Contains subject files and the correspondence of District Council Manager, Katie Quan, as well as miscellaneous correspondence.
- 6000/018 P: UNITE Pacific Northwest District Council Photographs, 1962-1997., This is a collection of over 400 photographs, chronicling rallies, conventions, meetings, etc. Members from the following organizations are pictured: ILGWU, Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance, Local 317, Local No. 8 of the Cloakmakers Union, the Laundry Workers International Union and UNITE.
- 6000/019: UNITE Department of Occupational Safety and Health Shop Files, 1995-2003., Contains subject files and OSH cases file alphabetically by employer.
- 6000/020: UNITE Research Department Files, 1995-1999., Contains files on employers, sweatshops, and NAFTA compiled by the Textile Workers Union of America (TWUA), the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers of America (ACTWU) and the International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU), as well as UNITE.
- 6000/020 P: UNITE Research Department Photographs, 1954-1977., Contains This is a collection of over one hundred photographs showing members on strike in Eutaw, Alabama; Miami, Florida; and New Berry, South Carolina; plus other locations that are unlabeled.
- 6000/021: UNITE Amalgamated Northeast Regional Joint Board Research Files, 1983-2002., Contains subject files and employer files, mostly alphabetical. Also contains files for organizing targets, especially in the Syracuse, NY, region.
- 6000/022 AV: UNITE Education Department Audio-Visual Materials, 1955-2001., Contains over 1000 video tapes. Subjects covered include: ILGWU conventions, sweatshops, the Triangle Shirtwaist Factory Fire, union officials, and many other topics.
- 6000/023: UNITE Vice President's Office Susan Cowell Files, 1995-2004., Contains mostly files on union elections and conventions, includes some ILGWU materials.
- 6000/024: UNITE Local 23-25 Records, 1982-2012., Contains speeches, press releases, General Executive Board minutes and materials, as well as material on various other subjects. Some of the records are from the International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU).
- 6000/024 AV: UNITE Local 23-25 Audio-Visual Materials, 1978-2005., Contains videos on union seminars, new members, sweatshops, NAFTA, immigration, and many other subjects.
- 6000/024 MB: UNITE Local 23-25 Memorabilia., Contains banners, buttons, posters, flags, and other union memorabilia.
- 6000/024 P: UNITE Local 23-25 Photographs, 1953-2003., Contains over 4600 photographs of members, celebrations, strikes, rallies and various other events are arranged in alphabetical order. Photo negatives and contact sheets are sorted by year. This collection includes photographs of the International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU).
- 6000/024 PUBS: UNITE Local 23-25 Publications, 1998-2003., Contains copies of Local 23-25 News, constitutions, stewards' handbooks, and other union publications.
- 6000/026: UNITE Office of Corporate and Financial Affairs Records, 1967-2003., Contains material on retirement, health, and dental benefit plans from various employers, such as Dixie Yarns, Pillowtex, and Fieldcrest. Also included are media articles and press releases.
- 6000/026 AV: UNITE Office of Corporate and Financial Affairs Audio-Visual Materials, 1987-1998., Contains audio and video cassette tapes largely about organizing campaigns.
- 6000/027: UNITE International Relations Department Records, 1977-2001., Contains files on labor and labor organizing worldwide. Inucludes correspondence with ITGLWF, FITTVCC/ORI, and Zensen. Much of the material is filed by country. This collection includes records of the International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU).
- 6000/027 PUBS: UNITE International Relations Department Publications, 1995-2001., Contains publications concerning labor in other countries. The first section is filed by country/region. That is followed by subjects arranged alphabetically, including child labor, globalization, women workers, and NAFTA. Also includes publicatins by ICFTU, ILO, ITGLWF, and the United Nations.
- 6000/029: UNITE Assistant to the President Alan Howard Files, 1991-2000., Contains corresponndence and information files on foreign workers and US companies. This collection includes materials of the Industrial Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU).
- 6000/030: UNITE Jeff Eichler Files, 1994-1999., Contains material on various city, town, and county governments committing to purchase union-made products.
- 6000/031: UNITE Ron Blackwell Collection of Country Files, 1988-1997., Contains material about Dominican Republic, Guatemala, Honduras, Mexico, and other countries. This collection includes files of the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union.
- 6000/032: UNITE Communications Department Jo-Ann Mort Files, 1985-2000., Contains press releases, articles, news clippings, and correspondence. Arranged alphabetically by subject. This collection includes files of the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU).
- 6000/033: UNITE Local 155 Records, 1997-2004., Consists of Local 155 Executive Board meeting minutes, communications, and manager's reports.
- 6000/033 P: UNITE Local 155 Photographs, 1995-1996., Contains over 200 photographs of Local 155 members, includes photographs of a sweatshop protest.
- 6000/037: UNITE Communications Department Records, 1962-2002., Contains newsletters, advertisements, and a listing of photographs from 1985-1997.
- 6000/037 AV: UNITE Communications Department Audio-Visual Materials, 1990-2003., Contains over 400 video cassettes of union activities and events.
- 6000/037 P: UNITE Communications Department Photographs, 1996-2004., Contains over 1000 photographs of UNITE rallies and demonstrations as well as various meetings, informational guides, family images and historical pieces.
- 6000/039: UNITE Organizing Department Records, 1940-2002., Contains memos, notes, broadsides, and authorization cards. Arranged alphabetically by employer. This collection includes files of the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) and the International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU).
- 6000/041 MB: UNITE Al Fox Tools Memorabilia, 1940., Contains various handtools used in the needletrades.
- 6000/042 MB: UNITE ACWA Jacob Potofsky Memorabilia, 1914-1976., Contains badges, buttons, and name tags from Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (ACWA), Textile Workers Union of America (TWUA), Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU), International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), and other unions.
- 6000/043 P: UNITE Editor Photographs, 1977-1991., This collection has over three hundred photographs and almost one hundred slides, showing members taking part in conventions and strikes.
- 6000/044 P: UNITE Photographs, 1920-2003., This is a collection of over twenty-five hundred photographs and over one hundred slides and several audio CDs. Pictures showing the history of UNITE, ACTWU, Labor Leaders, strikes, protests, boycotts, immigration and various types of labor actions.
- 6000/045: UNITE Southern Regional Joint Board Records, 1997-2003., Contains constitutions, meeting minutes, convention proceedings, and lists of shops.
- 6000/046: UNITE Immigration Project Records, 1991-2008., Contains publications, seminar materials, memos, correspondence.
- 6000/047: UNITE Muzaffar Chishti Papers, 1991-2001., Consists of records of the Council for American Fashions Labor-Management Industry Development Fund.
- 6000/048: UNITE Executive Assistant to the President David Melman Papers, 1989-1999., Contains industry reports and other research materials on employers. Arranged alphabetically by company, but contains only A - J.
- 6000/049 P: UNITE Local 9 Photographs., This is a collection of over one hundred photographs. Strikes, picketing, and meetings were all caught on film to show the history of Local 9.
- 6000/050: UNITE Local 10 and Local 23-25 Files, 1940-1997., Contains contract negotiation materials, scholarship records, song books, Executive Board meeting minutes, in addition to other subject files.
- 6000/050 AV: UNITE Local 10 and Local 23-25 Audio-Visual Materials, 1997-2003., Contains 30 video cassettes and 14 audio cassettes about the union and Local 23-25.
- 6000/050 MB: UNITE Local 10 and Local 23-25 Memorabilia, 1995-2004., Contains banners, buttons, awards, broadsides, and other memorabilia.
- 6000/050 P: UNITE Local 10 and Local 23-25 Photographs, 1998-2003., This is a collection of over three hundred photographs. Most of the photographs were taken between 1997 and 2000.
- 6000/050 PUBS: UNITE Local 10 and Local 23-25 Publications, 1995-2004., Contains Local 23-25 News, Garment Industry Day Care Center of Chinatown publications, and general UNITE union publications.
- 6000/052: UNITE Accounting Department File on Contractors, 1957-2003., Consists of audit record cards for contractors, arranged alphabetically. This collection contains a significant amount of material from ILGWU.
- 6000/053: UNITE Industrial Development and Labor Management Department Records, 1961-2002., Contains correspondence, memoranda, and reports. This collection contains a significant amount of material from ILGWU.
- 6000/055m: UNITE Organizational and Biographical History, 1998., Contains an alphabetical listing of union officials with their telephone numbers.
- 6000/056: UNITE Boston Joint Board Records, 1971-2005., Contains correspondence, contracts, local union member lists, subject files, and arbitration decisions.
- 6000/056 AV: UNITE Boston Joint Board Audio-Visual Materials, 1992-1999., Contains 59 video cassettes about the union and working in America.
- 6000/057: Carl Proper UNITE Papers, 1967-2005., Contains subject files, including material on the Council for American Fashions and the Needle Trades Action Project.
- 6000/057 PUBS: Carl Proper UNITE Publications, 1968-2011., Contains constitutions, financial reports, and reports on several aspects of the garment industry.